Meet the unsung heroes behind the greatest music of our time.
20 Feet from Stardom is a documentary, music film directed by Morgan Neville.
Backup singers live in a world that lies just beyond the spotlight.
Their voices bring harmony to the biggest bands in popular music, but we've had
no idea who these singers are or what lives they lead, until now.
Self, played by Darlene Love.
Self, played by Lisa Fischer.
Self, played by Merry Clayton.
Self, played by Judith Hill.
Self, played by Claudia Lennear.
Self, played by Tata Vega.
20 Feet from Stardom is a 2013 American documentary film directed by Morgan Neville and produced by Gil Friesen, a music
industry executive whose curiosity to know more about the lives of background singers inspired the making of the film.
Using archival footage and new interviews, it details the behind-the-scenes experiences of such backup singers as
Darlene Love, Merry Clayton, Lisa Fischer, Judith Hill, Jo Lawry, Claudia Lennear, and Tata Vega.
The film won the Academy Award for Best Documentary Feature at the 86th Academy Awards, 23 years after In the Shadow of
the Stars (1991), a similar documentary that focused on the members of an opera chorus, won the same award.
Lisa Fischer has said of backup singing:  "I reject the notion that the job you excel at
is somehow not enough to aspire to, that there has to be something more.
I love supporting other artists." She added: "Some
people will do anything to be famous.
I just wanted to sing."
In 2023, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically,
or aesthetically significant." It is the eighth film designated in its first year of eligibility, as well as the second most recently released film in the Registry.